ISMAIL HOSSAIN (IMON)

28TH OCT 1994 (NID), BANGLADESH

ADDRESS

Address : KA-57/2, Kuril Chowrasta,

Kuril Progati Sharani, Vatara

Dhaka-1229

E-mail : hossain.wbs.dev@gmail.com

Mobile +880 1705 723616



With over 6 years of experience in Computer Technology, I have developed a strong focus on both technical expertise and customer satisfaction. I am currently seeking a challenging and rewarding career that allows me to utilize my skills and experience to their fullest potential.

EMPLOYMENT DETAILS

CreativacIDA 28th Sep 2013 to 31th Aug 2015 Job Title: Lead Generation

- Overall responsibility for the company's Online marketing strategy.
- Adds posting on USA Classified site for generating leads.

Kernel BD Corporation 1st Nov 2015 to 31th Jan 2016 Job Title: Junior programmer

• Responsible for company's Web Development strategy.

Ekhanei.com 1st Mar 2016 to 31th Apr 2016 Job Title: Brand promoter

- Responsible for the company's Brand promoting strategy.
- Adds posting on Ekhanei.com.

British Council 1st May 2016 to 31th Jul 2016

Job Title: Marshal

- Complete all reports, logs and claims accurately and real time.
- Ensure that all test day procedures are met.
- To complete prescribed log sheets as directed by Exam Services.

Kiddo Land 28st Oct 2016 to 31th Jan 2017

Job Title: Web Developer

Responsible for the company's Web Development, Graphics & Social Media Marketing strategies.

DBN LTD.

Job Title: Web Developer

• Responsible for the company's Web Development, Graphics & Social Media Marketing strategies.

Freelancing 1st August 2018 to 1st May 2021

Position: Web Developer

• Responsible for developing Website, Graphics & Social Media Marketing strategies.

ilannoor Edification Ltd. 16th May 2021 to Running

Job Title: Web Developer

• Responsible for the company's Web Development, Digital Marketing & Technical Content strategies.

• Project Manager of ilannoor.com & ilannoor.institute.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

Commerce (SSC)	Abdul Khalique Memorial High School	Session: 2009
Diploma in Engineering (Computer Technology)	National Polytechnic Institute, Dhaka	Session: 2010-2011

PROFFESIONAL TRAINING & QUALIFICATION

- Web Developing by Kernel BD Corporation
- Digital Marketing by American Best IT
- Sales Training by Inside-out Institute

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Bengali : Proficient in reading and writing with a high level of fluency in verbal communication.

English : I possess excellent reading and writing skills, as well as intermediate proficiency in spoken

communication.

Skills

As a professional in the digital world, I understand the importance of technical content in optimizing a website for search engines. While the human mind perceives reality through sensation, search engines rely on technical content to index and rank websites. This is why a website must have dynamic and engaging content to effectively communicate with its audience and fulfill its intended purpose.

With my expertise in web design, development, and digital marketing, I am well-equipped to create content that is both aesthetically pleasing and technically optimized. My passion for programming and digital marketing is what drives me to constantly improve and stay up-to-date with the latest trends and techniques.

I believe that R&D, browsing, and working under seasoned professionals are great ways to further develop my skills and grow in this field. Ultimately, my goal is to use my knowledge and expertise to help businesses achieve their digital marketing goals and succeed in the online world.

COMPUTER SKILL's

- Operating System
- Microsoft Office
- E-mail & Internet
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Website Maintenance
- Server Management
 - WHM
 - cPanel
 - DigitalOcean
 - Hostinger
- Digital Marketing
 - Technical SEO
 - OnPage SEO
 - OffPage SEO
 - Social Media Marketing
 - Google Adwords
 - Google Search Console
 - Google my Business
 - Email Marketing
 - WhatsApp Marketing
 - SMS Marketing
 - B2C Marketing
 - B2B Marketing
- Programming Language
 - HTML
 - CSS
 - Bootstrap
 - PHP
 - MySQL
- Framework
 - Laravel
 - Codeigniter
 - WordPress
 - Opencart
 - Osclass
- Github

Some Example Works

Project Manager : <u>ilannoor.com</u> Project Manager : <u>ilannoor.institute</u>

Bootstrap/Laravel : <u>ilannoor.institute/career-planning</u>

Bootstrap/Laravel : <u>ilannoor.institute/al-arabiyah-baina-yadai-auladina</u>

Bootstrap/Laravel : <u>ilannoor.institute/the-glorious-quran</u>

Project Manager & Dev: codephics.com
Facebook Marketing: /ilannoor.ins
Facebook Marketing: /designwaybd
Facebook Marketing: /timersway

Facebook Marketing : <u>/oaheebookbd</u>

Disclaimer: Although I have managed & developed numerous projects in the past, the above mentioned ones are the only ones that are currently up and running.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Member of family

Father's Name : Abul Kalam Azad Mother's Name : Saleha Begum

Date of Birth : 28th OCT 1994 (NID) Nationality : Bangladeshi (By Birth)

3

Religion : Islam
Sex : Male
Marital Status : Married
Blood Group : B+

Date: 02-12-2023 Hossain
Signature